<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyber-Physical Systems Security Lab</title>
    <description>The CyPhy Lab is a part of the Information Assurance (IA) program with Dr. Irfan Ahmed serving as lab director.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 11:04:25 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 11:04:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>UNO Earns Grant to Study Cybersecurity Risks of Critical Infrastructure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;photo of the Dr. Irfan Ahmed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/news/ahmed2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right: 20px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of New Orleans will use grant from the U.S. Army Research Office to build equipment that will help address cybersecurity risks to the nation’s critical infrastructure, such as gas pipelines and power plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UNO researchers will create a so-called “test bed” of Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition systems, which is used to automate industrial and manufacturing processes. The growing trend of connecting these systems to a much larger network, such as the Internet or a corporate network, makes them susceptible to cybersecurity threats, according to Irfan Ahmed, assistant professor of computer science and the grant’s principal investigator. Dealing with those threats and determining vulnerabilities is an important task for utilities, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This equipment will greatly enhance UNO’s ability to deliver the full spectrum of cybersecurity skills needed in the profession,” Ahmed said. “This ‘test bed’ will be used for a variety of ongoing and proposed cybersecurity and forensics research projects at UNO.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “test bed” will contain scale versions of three different systems—a pipeline, a water treatment plant and a power plant—and will allow accurate simulation of each. The equipment will enable UNO’s computer scientists to research critical infrastructure protection which, according to Ahmed, is an area that receives insufficient attention given its importance to society at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uno.edu/campus-news/2015/UNO-Earns-Grant-to-Study-Cybersecurity-Risks-of-Critical-Infrastructure.aspx&quot;&gt;This news at UNO’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2016/07/08/grant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2016/07/08/grant.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UNO Students Study Cyber Attacks Using Utilities Simulator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/news/simulator.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo of the utilities simulator&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One million liters of sewage rushes into an Australian river and coastal waters. Eighty-thousand people lose power in the Ukraine. An oil pipeline explodes in Turkey and sixty hours of pipeline surveillance footage is erased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each of these real-world incidents, investigations turned up evidence of what went wrong—and what went wrong was cyber security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wastewater treatment plants, power plants and gas and oil pipelines can be easy targets for cyber attackers who seek to wreak havoc with just a few key strokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the University of New Orleans is training computer science students how to easily diagnose weaknesses in security systems that are designed to protect such automated processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uno.edu/campus-news/2016/UNOStudentsStudyCyberAttacksUsing96KUtilitiesSimulator.aspx&quot;&gt;Read full story at UNO’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2016/06/14/simulator.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2016/06/14/simulator.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UNO Professor Gets $300,000 Grant for Cybersecurity Peer Instruction Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/news/ahmed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo of the Dr. Irfan Ahmed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of New Orleans computer science professor Irfan Ahmed has received a 2-year $300,000 National Science Foundation grant to study how peer instruction techniques can improve cybersecurity education. Unlike the traditional lecture approach to teaching, peer instruction encourages every student to actively participate in discussions with fellow students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is one of the most strategically important areas of computer science, but also one of the most difficult to teach effectively, according to Ahmed. The vast majority of cybersecurity failures are the result of poor understanding of the security landscape and an inability to adapt to new threats, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We hope that peer instruction will be effective in improving learning outcomes in class and creating a mindset necessary for combating ever-evolving and more sophisticated cyber-attacks,” said Ahmed, an assistant professor of computer science and the grant’s principal investigator. “This will help students to develop the outside-the-box thinking that takes into account the incentives and capabilities of both the attacker and the defender.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uno.edu/news/2015/UNO-Professor-Gets-Grant-for-Cybersecurity-Peer-Instruction-Project.aspx&quot;&gt;Read full story at UNO’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/06/15/grant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/06/15/grant.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
